nicholsonsoftware@gmail.com https://github.com/anicholson44

Personal Mission Statement

To advocate for best practices that serve the customer, to use my expertise to solve complex and strategic problems, to own and drive product success, to mentor and help others achieve their goals, and ultimately to make lives better with the products my team creates.

Work Experience

Senior Full-Stack React/Ruby on Rails Engineer and Team Lead at Spatial Networks

March 2020 -- present, remote

- Lead development and take ownership over project success for strategic features using Ruby on Rails, React, and Postgresql
- Provide technical leadership and mentorship in the company's product-focused engineering team
- Advocate for and drive a cultural shift towards industry best practices around
 DevSecOps including automated testing, CI/CD, and Kanban

Full-Stack React/C# Engineer at Pluralsight, LLC

November 2018 - November 2019 in Salt Lake City, UT and remote

- Joined as part of 2019 acquisition of GitPrime, Inc.
- **Delivered high-visibility, strategic integration** between GitPrime and Pluralsight for Pluralsight Live conference three months after acquisition
- Engineered web applications with TypeScript, React, Redux, C#, and PostgreSQL

Full-Stack React/Ruby on Rails Developer at SciMed Solutions, Inc.

February 2016 - November 2018 in Durham, NC and remote

- Engineered web applications for clients in agricultural and medical research
- Consistently delivered high-quality software for SciMed's biggest clients using React, Redux, Ruby on Rails, and SQL databases

Full-Stack JEE Developer at Red Hat, Inc.

August 2013 - June 2015 in Richmond, VA and remote

- Worked on a high-priority ecommerce project where I mentored junior devs, and continued to be placed on high-visibility projects
- Managed client relations and expectations

Software Developer Intern at Noblis, Inc.

June 2012 - January 2013 in Danville, VA and remote

- Worked as part of a development team to build a web application for the FAA to interface with a Cray XMT2 supercomputer
- Was the only intern to secure a longer term position

Technical Expertise

Ruby on Rails, React, TypeScript, Postgres, Unit Testing, Unix Server Administration, CI/CD

Education

University of Virginia, College of Arts and Sciences, Charlottesville, VA August 2009 – May 2013

BA in Computer Science and Philosophy